so this written our discussion
is meta in our discussion so we're going
to be talking about
how we're going to be doing them in the
future mainly
so the first thing that's going to be
changing
based on a little bit of input from
others
is that instead of going through
voices with viveke episodes and so on
we're just going to go through awakening
from the meaning crisis
because in our first like
discussion after we sort of noticed that
the written our staff
kind of grinded to a help we decided
that
the reason it wasn't going very well was
because we weren't approaching it with a
problem formulation sort of attitude
and it took me all this time to realize
that well
awakening from the meaning crisis is
basically 50 hours of
problem formulation so it seems like we
should probably go through that first
and um make
as much like literally just mind this
you know my the gold mine i suppose of
information for uh
rutner um
obviously i'm aware brett you have
already made
quite a bit quite a few notes
on all the episodes have you done all of
the episodes
most of them there's a few at the
beginning i've missed but i can add into
them but uh yeah most of them are there
cool so there will be
brett's notes and this website
we found a while ago in the glossary
channel called
literally awakening from the meaning
crisis dot com
where someone has gone through
and uh started making a glossary
of terms and and so on um
and they've also provided like three at
least
on the first episode they provide three
different people's summaries
of the episodes so
as we go through these videos we can all
make our own notes and then we can check
brett's notes
we can check these other summaries
to enhance our own notes and then we'll
like
we'll want to do that so that when we
come back to discuss
what we've learned we won't be sort of
repeating what's already there
too much or we won't miss what's already
been written
now
so second of all
i'm thinking that as we do this
we might want to record
information a bit more
obviously we record it so far but we
feels like maybe we should
like i'm not saying we absolutely have
to because i'm not like in charge or
anything but
uh maybe we'd want to get this whole
wiki idea going i don't know
where that's actually gone in the past
i've seen some talk about it
and uh this guy who did the awakening
from the meanings crisis dot com
was kind of doing that but on his own
um so maybe we want to make our own
version because i've tried to contact
this guy who did it
and he is not responding i tried again
today
i've only sent one message so far
um yeah so mark mark's put together a a
wiki
in uh sort of soft launch uh form
uh so we so we have uh so we we do have
the
infrastructure right now for for the
wiki
uh so so that's so maybe mark can talk a
bit
about that yeah yeah there's some
information from written already in
there that
manuel mostly put in um
so we're gonna move that when we get a
new domain and
hopefully my service will be up this
weekend and we can uh we can
secure this thing and lock it down and
put accounts on it and all that right
now it's kind of wide open and
it's security through obscurity or
something um you know that's got like
lectio practice and a bunch of other
stuff on it but there's a whole section
for specifically for the religion that
is not a religion
and there's a whole like there's a list
of perennial problems
perennial needs right there's a bunch of
stuff already on there
you can look out and i'll just say that
the key
to a wiki the key to a wiki is
structuring it correctly
not that you can't restructure it but
you know
the problems that arise with wiki usage
and i've been using wikis for
way more years than most other humans
you know especially on large projects
we'll say
the key really is that because you can
put information in any format people
tend to put it in the wrong format for
accessibility and searchability
and then other people can't find it so
it doesn't do any good
so you just want to avoid that and you
know i'll help with that
to the extent that i can um and then
yeah at some point we're going to take
what we have on this test wiki
or soft launch wiki however you want to
frame it and and put it on a proper
domain
and you know hook it up to a website
right so the website will have a link to
the wiki or something
and other tools like that like forums
online
i want to turn off your mic if you're
not talking to us
i don't think any of us are named jasper
but i'd be interested no that's what
has to say i'm sorry
he has lots to say as a dog you know he
knows lots of things about religions
that are not religions
he's all connected you know i'm sorry i
thought my mic
was auto shut off my apologies i
probably all right
yes the state of the wiki so like i said
you know
uh mostly manuel put up a bunch of stuff
there
uh already and you guys are welcome to
put up more stuff as needed and then
we'll move it at some point
and you know it's it's already got three
phases
right problem definition figure out the
structure and then phase three was
to be determined as i'm looking at it
now
right so obviously you're talking about
oxfaratus
you're going to assume you mean you're
going to move it to another wiki with
like a
different name like retina or well i'm
gonna i'm gonna we're gonna have we get
we're gonna have a community wiki once
we decide on the
community name and get a domain for the
community name
it won't be awakening from the meeting
crisis.com obviously because that's
taken
too long but but but it'll be something
like that
right um and and you know we have some
possibilities already and
you know maybe it'll get folded into you
know the
reiki foundation stuff for something we
don't know yet right and then
when once that happens we will move what
is on this
server here to that new domain on a
different server
right and assuming i ever get my server
back up but
my my server should be up this weekend
so um
that that's kind of the plan so you
won't lose any work if you put it on rx
veritatis.com
and that is the citadel of truth after
all so um
it should go there for the moment okay
cool um so that's that's coming
soon then it's not down long down the
road
yes yes all of this is imminent within
this month
for sure almost certainly within this
month
very nice oh yeah and uh maybe
yeah so another one is maybe we want to
stick like a
group google doc or something in the
uh retina thingy
like the channels so that we could all
compile as we go through the week i
don't know
or maybe after we've had our discussion
about it
um yeah yeah for now for now google doc
is probably the best way to go
um there is a google doc like thing
that's free that i would put up
on one of my servers once i get my big
server working out
i'm planning on doing that as well
that's a little more problematic but not
super problematic but but
yeah we definitely need shared notes and
and you know they're beyond the wiki so
the wiki's sort of like formatted
right you want to have access to forums
right which is another thing i'm
i'm committing to putting up at some
point and then the forums will have a
written r forum and then you guys can do
the
sort of semi talk there instead of just
on discord we'll say
better search facilities for example
available on good form software
and then uh and then we'll have a shared
doc thing
or you can use google docs use google
docs for now obviously because my
stuff's not
not ready very nice
oh yeah and of course google docs or i
think we've
still got the crypt pad going there yeah
yeah i was going to say we want to
probably copy over
everything that's on that crypt pad
thing i don't know about using crypt pad
anymore because
at least when i used it was a bit slow
and we'd barely put anything on it and
it was already getting
slow i don't know if you had the same
thing
um
i understand some people may have a
problem with using google docs
uh well i don't
yeah i'm guessing no one does given the
silence
um if that guy who made awakening from
the meaning crisis dot com
does not respond and can't get us
access to it uh
yeah we should probably copy all that
over as well the relevant info
from the glossary
okay so um
now there's some
things to discuss i'll try and do the
shorter ones first
[Music]
um
we want shall we sort of re-jig
the channels so that it's
maybe got a bit more focused a
thing based on how we're gonna go
forward
like uh just general discussion
note sharing or something like that
any thoughts there
because it is basically dead at the
moment
what do you mean it's dead what's what's
dead about it
no one ever posts in the written
text channels anymore at this point
we get like i i look in there and see
something
like once every
like maybe three or four times a week
it's like one or two messages
and uh like if we tailor
the channels to what we're gonna do with
awakening from the minion crisis people
might and they put stuff in there and
because they feel like it's more
appropriate today
um well maybe we could also
start by asking what what is what's
slowing down
the people here are the people who are
most active
yeah in that forum what's stopping posts
in that forum
well yeah i don't know i think we
basically at the moment
just save everything for the
discussion and like topics like
structure
like that's sort of from when we were
just sort of
bashing our head against it rather than
formulating the problem
like i don't think like maybe we could
say stuff about structure but i'm not
sure there's a lot we could say about it
um obviously wiki is a good one
narrative and metaphysics
are like okay um
yeah anyway that's just something to
consider basically
um yeah and we can we and and if you
want
i mean i can add written our notes would
you like
yeah like notes discussions
sure
logically call it written our notes
cool
oh no aftmc notes because we're going
through this yeah
all right nice um
seeing as i really like to try and make
this as easy
as for everyone as possible
is there like
do you think there may be
a better time for this because
thursday's sort of a
funny day but i understand the weekend
may already have
quite a few things in it already
uh when this time works for me uh what
it
what what do people think a little later
would work better
for me but would be bad for velocin so i
can manage with this time
it just means that i have to be on mute
for most of the time
ah i mean it's not too bad for me
actually
because i basically live on american
eastern
time so despite living in
gmt i believe so
yeah we'll i'll just put it at 1am
my well not 1am your time it's 8pm there
you are
yeah so i'll i'll do that and see how it
works
how would 8 30 p.m be possible just
because
um my daughter goes to bed
at um somewhere between 8 20 and 8 30
so if it's eight o'clock then it can't
come at the beginning but i guess i
could come halfway through
half an hour in which is just fine
yeah i mean the discussion tends to last
two hours which
won't keep me up too late so i'll try
that too
if unless it's like a problem for
anybody else for it to get to that point
seems the answer is no
uh last thing to say the issue is that a
lot of the people
aren't here to be raised
say that again i think that a lot of the
people can't make this time aren't here
to tell us about it
they're self-selected
can already make this time so they don't
have a problem but you could be
excluding other people that haven't
because
[Music]
do written our discussion and we'll do a
poll and then we'll start to find out
you know where where people are at in
terms of what times they have available
for which sorts of things
and and we can have more more than one
meeting like we could have like a
eastern time zone meeting and
and a different time zone meeting too uh
so different people can do it
if you're doing video reviews or notes
reviews or something that that'll work
fine
right i mean but if you're doing like
organizational review then everybody has
to be there or something
right or at least a representative has
to be there from both groups or
something
yeah because otherwise we're having two
people we're two groups working in
parallel and that's
not really useful yeah
yeah that's sub-optimal i i i basically
chose this time
because well a i like it because
everyone else in my house is asleep so i
get quiet
but it's also after work and after
dinner for you
americans so which are just inevitably
the majority of the people here
because you've got so many people in
your country
um so it's probably going to be mostly
convenient for
that inevitably
so yeah we'll uh put that in the retina
like text channel and see if anyone
wants to shift it around
the last thing is that
i am like strewn brought up that he
didn't want
the voice of the vaki stuff to just
completely go away
um which
i think is fair because
like i still want to give awakening from
the minion crisis priority
um and it's probably good for us but
we'll see
but i think it's probably good for us
that we
alternate still because you know
making all these notes on a whole vid
that whole video in like a week
probably isn't maybe may not be viable
for a lot of people
and we want to be able to think things
through nicely don't we
and to keep up with all of the
info going on like wikis and
glossaries and so on but anyway
yeah like the the reason it might be
good to preserve voices with the fakey
stuff
is because it's more contemporary and uh
it it's it's coming out of a lot of
you know john being in dialogue with
like countless people who have improved
his thinking and offered new ideas and
so on
rather than us just relying on old
older info which only comes from john
so but i don't know how to fit that in
without us just doing a video every week
so we're having the people come over
right
for q and a's so i
i kind of want to do like a watch party
on on a video of a person coming over
just
to be prepared for the q a
and then there can be some discussion
around the video
during the watch party so
that's that's one option right and
well no don't i don't i don't want to
go to like a sleuth vietnam but like
there will be written or related stuff
there
i mean to some extent right there's zero
stuff that john's talking about that
isn't written are related
right which is why you're going to watch
the the series over again
so you know if you consider that then
any any of these voices for vaki
have at least a good potential of
shedding light on written our issues
and if we're doing uh these watch
parties which i think is a great thing
on the on the guest that we're having on
here for q a
and you know maybe that's enough fill in
to manuel's point but to solve both
problems
i mean yeah that's that sounds
satisfactory to me like
pretty much solves the problem
great i'm i'm i'm still
i'd still i guess i'd like to see what
stream thinks anyway
that doing watch parties to
fill in the voices with fakie hole
your mic's a bit funny cuts out a lot
sorry your mic's cutting out a lot so i
didn't hear what you just said
that was better yeah
um i was just saying well i'd have to
see what the watch parties look like
before i could
draw a conclusion okay
i mean i guess you could still prepare
stuff in advance of what
like going to the watch party you just
have to sort of
go along with the uh
format of like watch comment watch
comment
but yeah anyway
that's that took less time
than i expected it was only half an hour
i basically said everything i was gonna
say
so we can just go into the general
discussion now
which we would normally do
sorry do you want me to do you want me
to keep the recording going or
maybe for like half an hour longer or
something sure
if it's bought if it's boring i can turn
off
so if anyone's got any retina related
ideas to share go ahead i do not
i wish i did
oh and remember to make notes
on awakening from the meaning crisis
episode one
for next week
i will just say i guess in terms of
retina
and the people interested in written art
you know one thing that john's
made clear is the importance of the
ecology or practices
and yeah i thought you know so we're
doing
quite a bit of stuff here on the forum
and obviously you guys don't have to do
ecology of practices with us although
that would be great but
i think the people who are most
interested in are probably we have a
responsibility to
be following our own ecology or
practices and and obviously we're
we're here to try to help everyone do
that
yeah that was the note i forgot to
mention somehow
like yeah if you're really interested in
right now you need to do that too
because obviously the ecology practices
is probably the
center piece of the whole thing in the
end at least in my opinion
yeah okay so what so what main ecologies
of practices do we have
right now i know that the meditation is
a fairly big one
yeah so we've gathered it yeah there's
different pieces to meditation
right so he's got his own meditation
type
he's doing it in a specific order for a
specific reason which he explains in the
lessons
and then there's you know there's also
different forms so he's got the
the gong that you know that standing
moving practice
right and then he's got the seated
moving practice he's got chanting
in there that he's added in these are
all separate lessons right
and uh and he's got lectio divina and
then we have a group like geopractice
that we do based on john stuff
right and then and then he's gone into
the epicureanism
and now we're in stoicism so there's a
bunch of practices in there
like maximization and
a philosophical fellowship and
you know journaling your cognitive
biases
right and and actually we need a better
list i've been talking about this for a
while and
i haven't sat down and done it um but
yeah he kind of sneaks in some of these
practices
in the middle of the lesson instead of
you know
he just changed formats basically when
we switch to the western traditions
uh outlined in uh wisdom of hypatia um
so yeah we we definitely need
a better list for the we'll say the
western stuff i
i think we have meditation notes that
are fairly complete both brett and i
that talk about all the meditation side
stuff or most of it anyway
and then there is a set of notes on uh
wisdom of hypatia
chapter four which is the uh epicurean
stuff
uh so those notes are available um i i
did those notes
um and and then like i said we need to
go through the newer newer lessons
and uh pick up on all the things that
that john's talking about because he's
he keeps sneaking in practices sort of
in the middle
and he's not as uh as sort of
uh clear about it uh as he was right so
he's got self-examination
journaling looking for commission
omission bias and virtue
stoic daily reading out of a particular
book and that's part of maximization
creating maxim
right and now he's got this new thing
where you're supposed to practice deep
learning on the maximums that you
produce
so there's a whole bunch of stuff that
we're trying to
formalize and support each other and
account to each other
so those are sort of groups we're trying
to get going
so we could mutually support each other
right and john specifically called out
the discord server
in the lesson as the place to go to
do some of these practices with people
that's why we renamed
the ritual halts the grove and we're
following the epicurean
practices there with their grove idea
and
you know trying to get us to do this
basically right to involve ourselves as
the hub we'll say of the
ecologies of practice based off of the
youtube lessons that he's still
that are still ongoing right and so
we're i think we're
most of the way through stoicism
although i need to catch up in the book
myself uh and then we're gonna move on
to
neoplatonism and i don't know what if
anything he has planned after that
but it's worth at least engaging in the
lessons playlist for the meditation
theories
because as it turns out the meditation
series turned into an ecology of
practices
series and it's just named meditation
due to historical
action
so i guess the question is is everyone
interested in
in joining us on this uh ecology of
practices journey and
and again you can do your own thing you
don't have to deal with it with us but
it's nice doing it together
and working together and supporting each
other on in it
right and then more to the point i think
to the point of retinar
i would say that you know if you think
that that engaging
with uh the you know original material
is important
i would say that explicitly that the
meditation lesson in particular although
all of the meditation theories is
excellent because he does q and a's in
his
q and a's are fantastic um especially
his answers
um are are you know that's
really important right because that is
the occur those are part of the
practices that he wants you to
to engage with in your own personal
ecology
and just understanding that because he
does go into a lot of the science
during those lessons just understanding
what he's talking about there
uh you know might give you a better idea
in terms of well here's the practice
the practical implementation the actual
practices
that he's embodied himself that he
thinks are
part of uh enabling this
uh new
[Music]
this new mode of engaging with the world
you know based on
on this uh principles that that i think
he's trying to embody for
for written r in particular
speaking of which how's that uh
schematizing the practices coming
uh well exactly zero work has been done
because i was on vacation and
um i need to get back on that for sure
but there's a bunch of stuff going on so
we'll see which
which which thing bubbles up first um
yeah the next step in the schematization
is actually just for me to sit down and
and use our our little model that we've
come up with to see
if that helps us or if that is not
helpful
so that is that is definitely ongoing
work and it is actually about half done
so i just need to finish uh going to the
last stage of the transformations i was
trying to do to get the schematization
we'll say to work and then and then we
have to send it off to john and see what
he thinks
sort of thing and i guess
another project written our related
project
is coming up so cali came up with some
some good rituals but i think we want to
you know come up with more rituals
that are written are you know more
directly written or related into the
to the lessons that you know john's been
talking about and after mc and all that
so that can be a project of coming up
with
modern day rituals for for retina
and you know experimenting and
expanding and so on
you know that serious play
all right so uh we the the problem is
that we're still trying to get
get the problem formulation done right
so we can't say
let's create a ritual for this and the
ritual for this and a ritual for this
because we might find out in the end
that only a and b were problems and b
is actually i guess we could but
we have to be ready to throw away quite
a bit of the work
i i was going to say it's okay to like
experiment with it
it's okay well it's it's even necessary
right because you need to
you need to figure out what makes a good
ritual and
and how how you can do all the things
that
are in a ritual and like that's really
hard
so it's it's not like we can just make
rituals and then
it's okay like that's an evolving
process
and like in every tradition which was
fade
and get generated over time so like i
don't see that as a
issue no what i mean is what do we need
a ritual for
like that's a basic fairly basic
question
we don't want to be creating rituals
with no purpose but at the same time if
we don't
know precisely what the problem is we
don't know okay
what solutions what can we put in
rituals to be a solution
what kind of rituals do we need
right but i think again that falls back
on on what manuel was saying
is that regardless of whether or not you
actually understand there's so much work
that needs to go into understanding
rituals and just trying things out
that it's worth it try things out
because you're gonna
knowing that you're gonna throw most of
it away anyway until problem formulation
is done we'll say
but then when you get that point
whoever's off doing the ritual
uh or whatever parties are off doing the
ritual project will be ready
to put together higher quality rituals
when
when you know when we know what what's
which specific
point they need to hit or something and
that's part of say the experimentation
so one of the things that we did already
with the group let's go practice was you
know we we came up with some
some theories about how this might work
right based on
john doing the lectio as part of his
lesson
and we put together a couple of theories
we tried a couple of different formats
uh and then we figured out which format
was best and then we
kept iterating and making it better and
now we have you know a really cool group
lectio practice that
that donna has seen and commented on
you know unless i'm misremembering and
he really liked it
so and and that's part of his mission
anyway is the experimentation side right
he's rather explicit about that
uh you know we we kind of helped out on
that right so
that was very useful what do we don't
know what we need a ritual for so
we can create five different rituals
to kill your past self do we need a
ritual ritual to kill your past self
maybe probably but on the other hand we
we don't know that we need
that kind of a ritual do we need a
ritual
to um make yourself more dedicated
to what you're trying to do in the
future possibly is that best done in a
ritual or is that best done in something
else
well the experimentation is more around
what makes a good ritual
so just picking a random thing like oh i
want a ritual that enhances my video
game playing
has value in and of itself because
learning how to put rituals together and
what works to make rituals work in
different contexts
is in and of itself useful i think that
was more
to the point that manuel was making
originally and
and and that work hasn't been done and
to the extent that it's an experiment
and we might throw it all out fair
enough
um but learning how to do it and how it
or at least coming up with theories
about how it might work
and what the utility is and what things
maybe we can't do with rituals because
we can't
figure out a way to you know facilitate
that and ritual help us
because then we can go oh look we tried
to come up with a ritual for this and
and maybe we're just you know maybe
we're not smart enough to or whatever
but but that's fair too then then this
group
can't make a ritual around that maybe we
need to facilitate that
you know psychotechnology or or you know
whatever requirement
some other way and so just having that
information in of itself is useful
and of course only if people want to
take a take on the gauntlet right like
if no one wants to do it or we don't
have the manpower or whatever then
that's fine too but
you know if people are looking for ways
to contribute that's one way to
contribute that is definitely useful
even if you end up throwing out you know
most of the actual product
because the result of generating the
product will generate a bunch of
information that will be useful going
forward
yeah ideally there will be different
groups working on different things so
this
these aren't projects that everyone has
to be working on
you want to find people with who have
certain interests
you know in these areas to do to do
certain things like that
so i created i think it was three ritual
ideas that are currently in the crypt
pad
um has anyone read through them or tried
them out i kind of tried out one of them
at
summer solstice
i haven't seen it do you want to give a
brief description
not really because i'm on my phone well
actually i can probably
have it open at the same time
just give me a minute
for the crypt pad to open
yeah i didn't engage with the uh [ __ ]
pad ritual
so not familiar with it
so i put in um three
we're talking about uh rituals for a
while so i put in three
um ritual
ideas um
so one was a festival celebrating order
slash the rational side of the psyche
um celebrated on winter solstice or the
shortest
day of the shortest day of the year and
i was suggesting quiet contemplation of
the self from sunset to midnight
um of what the of the self in the past
year and the aspects that you want to
sacrifice and
who you want to become in the coming
year so for self-improvement
and then at midnight um basically
it re basically like the fire ritual
where you you've written down what you
want to sacrifice
and uh of what part of yourself you want
to sacrifice and you put it in the fire
and
tell everyone else um who what you're
sacrificing and what you want to become
and so that way you're mo it's to
motivate change and self and development
of the self because your
kind of thing is spending time to think
deeply about
who you are and who you want to be and
figuring out okay what do
what changes do i need to make to become
who i want to be
and stop being these parts of me myself
that i don't like
naturally interesting yeah so that has
elements of john's
uh practice uh nightly practice the
commission omission
and yeah yeah that's great
yeah and then um uh on the summer stop
solstice do a festival celebrating
chaos and the emotional side of the
psyche so have like a community
gathering with a
community dinner or potluck and then
like
creativity so music and singing and
ecstatic dancing
and pain painting your faces or
what i ended up doing actually um when i
kind of tried this was um i got sidewalk
chalk and
um drew we drew all over the
um driveway and um everyone everyone had
well now a bunch of people brought
instruments to try to play music
and then i was saying um suggesting
music and singing and stories and jokes
and
creativity and then
at midnight or whatever time works best
do a ritual where everyone's
directing matter to people close to them
the community in the world
so maybe sitting in a circle and doing
it meditatively or maybe doing it
while dancing and singing and shouting
that's really cool
and then i was trying to figure out some
kind of something to celebrate
uh festival of of the dead so uh
celebrating death as part of the journey
and just an element
and um the ritual i suggested
associated with that is at some point
maybe sunset
um community gathering in a place of
remembrance like a graveyard
and everyone bringing a candle and
taking it in turns to step forward and
light the candle
and say the name of the person who died
the last year along with a brief
sentence about them
and then have the community direct
matter towards
that person's family or community
for um remembrance and communal grieving
wow
yeah i think that's that's i don't make
maybe we discussed it in the text
channel like before
but that that sounds like some of the
ideas i've thought
so i like it so far
yeah absolutely
and this might like i i've thought maybe
another side project for the writers
and the poets and the philosophers to
get together
is to create new new modern
you know mythos and you know we could
come up with stories
you know that go along with each of
those as well
that would be really interesting to try
well i did today something along those
lines expect
yeah quite a lot actually
i was just saying uh just um i remember
suggesting some of that with respect to
a narrative around
zombies and and manner and potential
the soul i don't know that way
yeah we were kind of having a discussion
a discussion about rituals in the
channel and then coffee was
that said guys stop me don't just make
stuff up for no reason
and um so i took those ideas
from what we were discussing and like
put them together and added
other things and
yeah so that that sort of stuff can go
on the wiki or
or wherever but you know like like like
i said the group
lectio practice already has a bunch of
documents uh they're not complete but
they're actually 90
complete uh so that people can just
practice the group lectio
right it's got a you know if you're the
facilitator is the theory it's got a
document a theory a documentation on
facilitator and then the reader
and then the participants and and all
the responsibilities so people know how
to engage with
with we'll say that practice so the
rituals be the same sort of thing right
like here's the format of the ritual his
theory behind the ritual
and then here's here's something that
explains uh what you do
in the actual ritual other components
oh yeah and uh i really like the idea of
um swapping
the time of years that you had for
like the rational and the uh
chaotic one because you want everyone to
be as jovial as possible in the dead of
winter
and i guess most and most people are in
the northern hemisphere so
no no no um so the idea is that it's it
it um
is practicing a different day on the
northern and south southern hemisphere
all right so you practice it at your
winter solstice
so if you're in the southern hemisphere
then that's what's considered in the
middle of summer for the northern
hemisphere
yeah so
i want to introduce something that i
think might be the most important thing
is
and it's like a mechanism for giving
feedback
on things where when people start trying
stuff out that we have
a format of gathering information like
what what what do people need to pay
attention to
when they're trying to give feedback
like
i think it's really valuable to
systematize that
and then find a way like
i don't know maybe like a google form or
whatever right where we
can start gathering this information
because i think
that's that's maybe the thing that has
been lacking most up
until now like the way that we
receive feedback from people
so something like this worked really
well this didn't work very well
this is the the main thing i really
enjoyed these are the things i really
didn't like
this is what i'd do differently next
time
yeah but yes and yep and for each
participant
if if they're willing like you don't
want to force people right i want to say
if you're doing this right
you have to fill out the form but having
a form
right because again this goes back to
tron you know part of transmission
is experimentation well if you're going
to get
do experiments you need to gather data
right and so
you need a formal way of gathering the
right kind of data
so that when people engage in these
practices you actually have something to
look back on so that you can improve
because everybody talks about improving
the practices and then doesn't gather
the data
and so it's not possible to improve
practices
and we got to remember right like so for
example if we're doing this right
hemisphere thing right like the whole
purpose of
the thing is to accentuate
the symbolism of the right hemisphere
right so
yes we want to have fun but we need we
need to have
fun in remembrance of
the right hemisphere right so so the
feedback needs to be in
in that context because if if we're just
gonna have a festival that's
that's not uh doing anything
significant in relation to the symbology
then like
it's it's worthless for its function
right like then it's just a day to get
together
that's the whole point with that i was
making with all right so don't make
don't make rituals for no
reason though and we don't know the
reasons that we need rituals for
well yes right but we
so so first of all when i think about a
ritual i think
like like more in the sense that mark
said like not something that's once a
year but like
something you do regularly to remind you
of the thing for example
right and and
the the the reminding right that can
happen like once a year or they can
happen like
every week or every day even is
is the important part of the ritual
right so so in a sense it's it's
upkeep right you you're doing
mental health
clearing or whatever right and
so so what what you what you want from
the mid
ritual mostly is that it's easily
accessible right so it's low
cost to maintain it and it's also
fulfilling the function that you require
so so getting information about
how it's fulfilling the function that we
wanted to fulfill
that that is more what i'm talking about
with feedback
so less of a did you like it didn't you
like it but moreover did it do its job
right i mean right or important but yeah
did it
yes maybe some way to measure the effect
which is
would you do it again yep exactly
yeah because if people won't do it again
it doesn't matter yeah
and and and like right like how do you
think it could go better
right and then you need to also
articulate the context in which it can
go better
right and then so that's that's all
not straightforward stuff i guess that's
what i wanna what i mean
everybody can pump together a form right
but
form needs to have the right questions
to gather the information and that's
a little bit harder i mean kind of but
at the same time it's pretty similar to
the
um plan do reviews um cycle that
uh happens with iterative development
right you're saying all right so
what what could what went well and badly
what could we do
next time to um so that everything works
better
except that what you're trying to work
bet what you're trying to have work
better isn't necessarily a program or
something like that
it's whatever the purpose of the ritual
or festival was
yeah that basic format worked great in
all contexts and yeah certainly software
development stole it from other places
that were doing it for
quite quite a bit longer we'll say but
you do have to customize it for the
ritual
and yeah there's a bunch of stuff that's
always the same like would you do it
again
how did you feel blah blah blah but
there's also a bunch of stuff to
emanuel's point that's going to be
specific
and tailored to that particular ritual
to make sure that we're capturing
whether or not or maybe how much of the
intended purpose is
actually working for the for the
audience
i think we've covered some good stuff
tonight
so does anyone have feedback on the on
those rituals or is it uh
let's wait and try them out a couple
times and see
not necessarily once a year
well like i i'd add more stuff right um
like like the ecology of practices you
you
you generate uh you're saying additional
things not
um also do x y and z at
a rich at ritual
uh no no no like if if if you
like so what you were talking about
mainly were like like holidays right
which i think it's an
awesome idea to have holidays uh to
specific
uh um
but then right like when
when something like that occurs then
there's a lot of
different people with different
interests that will
uh will show up right so everybody needs
to have something that's
suitable for them right like not
everybody is going to have
the same interest the same capacity like
needs to be something for the kids right
i like all of that stuff right like if
you want to get serious about it
uh so so yeah that that's something that
should be added over time so i i figured
out now how to do the reaction rolls
so what i'll be doing probably next week
is setting up
where people can sign up for things like
you know ritual committee or
you know mythos committee or the various
different groups
and uh you know we can start having
working groups i think those were all
great ideas
that should be worked and developed and
played around with and experimented with
my idea was that um different
communities would have different ways of
doing things so some communities
um they might have like more people who
want to sit around telling stories so
they'd do more sitting around telling
stories unless running around and
shouting and
making music and um that like different
communities and
different subgroups within the
communities would kind of develop
naturally as someone
decided okay i'm going to go over here
and do some painting and then
say five other people think oh hey
painting's a good idea i'll come do
painting with you
right like i agree that
that will naturally happen and that's
something you want right
but when when we're designing something
right we're designing something
so like
when we when we want a holiday or
whatever right like
we we have to choose
what we want in it and how how how we
get it right like
you're gonna have to do it top down
because else it's just like
yeah some some empty shell that's that's
mean
like you need to have the coherence to
have the meaning
i think those ideas are really great
chevron thanks for
workshopping that
yeah i think the ideas what i heard they
are at least aimed on the right
did anybody else want to sign up to get
involved in
some particular like mythos or more
rituals or
note-taking or something else i mean
it looks like we get a lot of people
here but not you know not everybody has
something to do we'll say so
so a little thought i i keep having
for the past few days is uh maybe this
whole idea of oh we sign up for certain
projects
is maybe not the right way to
frame it if we've got this wiki thing
going
all the projects are available to
everyone all the time
and then you can just kind of join in
on whatever you want at any time
yeah and the idea of roles are that
sorry sorry the idea
of the roles are that if you could have
everybody who has an interest in it
and if you want to just draw everyone's
attention you can do it you can add them
right so you can yeah
okay the benefit of having groups though
is that kind of there's
there's these people over here who are
meant to be doing this
have they done it if so then great if
not
then hey guys why can you get some work
done if you have some time
right so the format i put on the wiki
initially or
emmanuel and i put on the wiki initially
for the written our project is that you
have an owner
maybe two owners right and then that way
people can sign up and say i'm working
on this with this person
and the purpose of having an owner is
that if you don't have an owner and you
don't have a way to track progress
the inner development model doesn't work
right
nothing to iterate on because no one's
responsible for anything
and when no one's responsible for
something it will not get done
right i can tell you this from over 30
years of project management experience
it will not get done if there's no owner
like
ownership is key
and yes anybody can contribute at any
time whether they're listed as a
you know on the project or not that's
easy to
do but you still have to have somebody
you know who's responsible for
delivering something at some point
it doesn't have to be a specific time
frame but you do want to see progress
over over at least months otherwise
things won't
won't actually happen
in any groups you guys want me to make
just let me know and i can create the
groups
well i think here's a question that i
could ask that um
can you guys hear me yep yep
yeah okay so um the people that haven't
spoken
um what would you guys like to see out
of a religion that's another religion
anyone maybe rephrase it a little bit uh
what do you think like what's one of the
things you think
the religion that's not a religion has
to do
that maybe you haven't seen people
mention yet
yeah well i mean like you know people
are here for the meeting for a reason
it's like what is your interest you know
what what
what got you here because the fact that
people are quiet like this actually
that perturbs me slightly um
it seems like people don't well my
concern is that people don't see the
room to engage in
the thing that interests the first and
so i really want to make sure that we
know what that is
and some people may just be interested
they're interested in the project and
they just want to listen
so uh but uh yeah yeah well if that if
that's the case then you know
just just say that that's higher you
know it's my interest
yeah definitely if if
yeah if people are just casually
listening in and they have i mean you
know
ninja happy to have you along as well
yeah we definitely want to hear if
somebody feels that
they feel that there isn't a place for
them and they they'd want there to be
so yeah please either now or after uh
yeah let us know
we don't want to put you on the spot
you guys are just going to continue with
the watch parties like watching and then
commenting at the same time
because um i know strewn was mentioning
he wanted to have some place for that
which is also
one of the things i was more interested
in like keeping up with the discussion
that vervice is doing with
john's doing with other people as well
and then
yeah i was just mostly curious to see
what this restructuring was for tonight
but
um i was also curious if there's like
some sort of
schedule i couldn't find it for like the
lectio divina sort of thing and then
i assume the wisdom of hypatia that's
just following along with
john's new videos on the western
tradition
yeah so so familiar with the calendar
yeah
because i should not remember it
so yeah in announcements the pinned post
and announcements has
has a link so you push the push pin at
the top
and that will give you a link to our
google calendar and there's a non-google
version as well
uh we're working on i think algernon's
working on uh creating a group
for wisdom of hypatia so that's in in
the works
uh but uh you can also bring up wisdom
of hypatia in our morning
meditation post meditation discussions
uh but we're probably gonna have
something
more broad of that soon and uh
and yeah we're we're we've started this
week we started uh
listening parties to our voices of
verviki uh guest
uh guests lecture so we're gonna keep
that going
although greg enriquez he has three so
maybe we'll just choose one
but yeah
yeah then we have another afternoon
meditation right and then there's a
meditation being run for the european
i would imagine you can discuss any of
the
practices from john and in any of those
forums with other people and then of
course
if people are around uh most of the
people who are around say
hang out and voice chat uh are happy to
engage with some of those topics too
if there's you know if the right people
are there or whatever because a lot of
the people that are there
are familiar with the meditation series
so
um and the group lectios on sunday
usually
although occasionally we try it on
saturday as well so
there's plenty of stuff on the calendar
and and if the you know if we need more
stuff or people want to do stuff in
in european time zones or such not then
my group lectio like i said we actually
have all that or not all of it but most
of it written down
if somebody wanted to run it they
probably could um
you know without too much coaching we'll
say
okay great thanks um so the watch
parties are the thing you mentioned with
three with greg henriquez that would uh
that would be before uh or or
yeah before the the q a uh so so i
haven't booked the other ones yet but
i'm gonna
book uh book listing parties in the
schedule before each of the
voices before each of the guests so last
time we did it the day before
we won't always be able to do it the day
before but uh yeah well i mean i've got
to look at the schedule this weekend
and yeah and we can always do
spontaneous
yeah yeah absolutely if you just want to
pop in and say hey guys
in 10 minutes i want to do this then
there's probably some people who will
join you
yeah absolutely
the listening party chat you know voice
chat is there all the time
so
okay i think recording can end now
if it's still going all right thanks
veloskin this is great